# Vishnu Parasuramuni

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPER



Experienced front-end developer with a strong focus on JavaScript, React, Next, and Angular. Dedicated to delivering high-quality work and promoting collaborative teamwork. Enthusiastic about exploring the latest front-end technologies and poised to bring expertise and innovation to the team.

• Hyderabad, India 🛛 vishnuthecoder@gmail.com 📞 9967570182 🕜 comaecod.github.io/portfolio

in in/vishnu-parasuramuni-b19427190/

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Zenoti

FULL STACK DEVELOPER, Currently Working

- Actively develop and maintain a cloud-based SaaS using Angular, JavaScript, .NET, SQL.
- Optimize and enhance the SaaS to improve performance and deliver features for clients.

#### Meraai

FULL STACK DEVELOPER, January 2023 - March 2023

- Worked on developing a PWA using React Vite, Framer, and MUI.
- Contributed to Spring Boot and gained insights into the CI/CD pipeline.
- Enhanced development skills and acquired knowledge of modern software practices.

## Tata Consultancy Services

DEVELOPER & CODE EXPERT (JAVASCRIPT + REACT.JS), February 2020 - January 2023

- Upgraded front-end from Struts/JSP to React.js and collaborated with the back-end team.
- Developed reusable components, improving performance and load time while enhancing user experience.
- Boosted productivity by 30% and reduced load time by 50%.

## **EDUCATION**

Sastra University, Thanjavur

MASTERS IN COMPUTER APPLICATIONS (8.9 CGPA), February 2022 - February 2024

Jai Hind College, Mumbai

B. VOC. IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT (9.6 CGPA), July 2016 - March 2019

## **TECHNOLOGIES I'VE WORKED ON**

JavaScript	Angular	Next.js	React.js
Typescript	jQuery	Tailwind	NGRX
CSS	.NET MVC	Springboot	SQL Server

## **LANGUAGES**

English	Hindi	Telugu	Spanish

## HOBBIES

Playing Chess	Playing Guitar	PC Gaming	Sleuth Movies
Cosmology	Reading English Literature	Carnatic Classical (Vocal)	Playing Piano